"Episode 14"
"에피소드 14"
"to let go"
"놓치다"
But you are one year older than me.
그런데 당신은 나보다 한 살 더 많아요.
I give it to you as your original property.
나는 그것을 당신의 원래 재산으로 당신에게 줍니다.
Is it the original property?
원래 재산인가요?
to let go
놓치다
What nonsense are you talking about?
무슨 말도 안되는 소리를하는거야?
Don't run away.
도망치지 마세요.
“Archian”
"아치안"
"Look at."
"바라보다."
“It’s clear outside.”
"밖은 맑아요."
Madam, Madam Hua sent someone.
부인, 화 부인이 누군가를 보냈습니다.
Questions about...
에 대한 질문...
About the brothers of the Lord
주님의 형제에 대하여
“I’m dreaming again.”
"나 또 꿈을 꾸고 있어."
What perfume do you use to dry your clothes?
옷을 말릴 때 어떤 향수를 사용하시나요?
It smells very familiar.
아주 익숙한 냄새가 나요.
Where do I get my emotions from? Take some incense.
내 감정은 어디서 얻나요? 향을 가져가세요.
How about drying laundry during this time?
이 시간에 빨래를 말리면 어떨까요?
Madam, please tell me.
부인, 말씀해주세요.
A thing to do
해야 할 일
with your younger brother
네 동생이랑
government
정부
Madame Chao
마담 차오
Madam, let’s play with the shuttlecock.
부인, 셔틀콕을 가지고 놀자.
Come quickly, madam.
빨리 오세요, 부인.
Come visit us, ma’am.
놀러오세요, 부인.
government
정부
Madam, would you like some He Tao?
부인, 허타오 드실래요?
It will help you keep your mind clear.
정신을 맑게 유지하는 데 도움이 될 것입니다 .
government
정부
Maid Lee, what should we do?
메이드 리, 우리는 어떻게 해야 할까요?
ma'am...
부인...
I think it would be best to go back to your room and rest.
방으로 돌아가서 쉬는 게 좋을 것 같아요.
There is no use waiting here.
여기서 기다려도 소용없습니다.
Asen is still suffering in prison.
아센은 아직도 감옥에서 고통받고 있습니다.
Please let me sit in the room. How can I feel comfortable?
방에 앉게 해주세요. 어떻게 하면 편안함을 느낄 수 있나요?
Asen is our only son.
아센은 우리의 유일한 아들이에요.
I hope it doesn't do anything.
나는 아무것도하지 않기를 바랍니다.
until the judgment is confirmed
판결이 확정될 때까지
But we can't sit still and do nothing.
하지만 우리는 가만히 앉아서 아무것도 할 수 없습니다 .
Peace...
치안어...
She is truly the mistress of the Zhong family.
그녀는 진정한 Zhong 가족의 여주인입니다.
I don't know how many people they sent there.
얼마나 많은 사람을 그곳으로 보냈는지 모르겠습니다.
to ask her for help
그녀에게 도움을 요청하기 위해
If I hadn't punted it myself.
내가 직접 펀팅을 하지 않았다면
She didn't even think to say anything.
그녀는 아무 말도 할 생각조차 하지 않았습니다.
I don't think she cares.
나는 그녀가 상관하지 않는 것 같아요.
He is her only brother.
그 사람은 그녀의 유일한 동생이에요.
then...
그렇다면...
Should I go see that person again?
그 사람을 다시 만나러 가야 하나?
She won't care. You can use the servants I sent.
그녀는 상관하지 않을 것입니다. 내가 보낸 하인들을 이용하시면 됩니다.
But if you're a mom like me, but we need to talk.
하지만 당신이 나 같은 엄마라면 하지만 우리는 대화를 해야 합니다.
Would you like to sit down first?
먼저 앉으시겠어요?
This is the era of chisels and ax faces.
이것은 끌과 도끼 얼굴의 시대입니다.
It is not recommended to go to the head family residence.
종가 저택에는 가지 않는 것이 좋습니다.
The owner is still angry.
주인은 여전히 ​​화를 내고 있습니다.
If you go often
자주가신다면
The master will become even colder.
주인님은 더욱 차가워지실 겁니다.
Wear Qian'er.
Qian'er를 착용하십시오.
So what should I do?
그래서 내가 무엇을해야하니?
Qian'er was afraid that he would become like that...
Qian'er는 그가 그렇게 될까 두려웠어요...
It's such a pity that the hostess's position was taken away...
여주인의 자리를 빼앗긴 게 너무 안타까워요...
Are you going to get your brother in trouble?
형님을 곤경에 빠뜨리실 겁니까?
I think...
제 생각에는...
Qian'er must have other plans.
Qian'er에는 다른 계획이 있어야 합니다.
What plans could she have?
그녀는 어떤 계획을 가질 수 있었습니까?
If she had other plans
그녀에게 다른 계획이 있었다면
Why did you ignore the person I sent?
내가 보낸 사람을 왜 무시했나요?
honey
여보
It could be so
그럴 수도 있다
Someone knows her secret.
누군가 그녀의 비밀을 알고 있습니다.
Her mouth watered.
그녀의 입에 군침이 돌았다.
I can't help it, Asen publicly
어쩔 수 없어 아센 공공연히
What's the secret?
비밀은 무엇입니까?
I do not know.
모르겠습니다.
However, it is best not to do anything hastily.
하지만 성급하게 아무것도 하지 않는 것이 좋습니다.
Now, have some tea first.
자, 먼저 차를 마셔요.
I don't want to drink.
나는 마시고 싶지 않습니다.
I am worried about both Assen and ASEAN . I don't think it would be good.
아센과 아세안 모두 걱정이 되네요. 안 좋을 것 같아요.
I know you love sweets.
나는 당신이 과자를 좋아한다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
Try it and see if you like it.
시도해보고 마음에 드는지 확인하십시오.
The desserts here are very delicious.
이곳의 디저트는 매우 맛있습니다.
A few days ago, Ye Ran married his concubine.
며칠 전 예란은 그의 첩과 결혼했다.
Are you going to join in on the fun?
당신도 이 재미에 동참할 건가요?
Accept it.
그것을 받아들이십시오.
I didn't go to my senior's wedding.
나는 선배 결혼식에 가지 않았다.
when he married his wife
그가 아내와 결혼했을 때
This time I will compensate you.
이번에는 제가 보상해 드리겠습니다.
You are the leader of the Zhong family.
당신은 종 가족의 지도자입니다.
Even if you don't go, you won't be considered. It's not appropriate.
가지 않더라도 고려되지 않습니다. 적절하지 않습니다.
He is my senior.
그는 나의 선배입니다.
You should at least go and see it.
적어도 가서 봐야 해요.
I know you two are close.
나는 너희 둘이 친하다는 것을 알고 있다.
From childhood
어린 시절부터
So what happened? With the painter's son?
그래서 무슨 일이 일어났나요? 화가의 아들과 함께?
Why is he in prison?
그는 왜 감옥에 갇혔습니까?
As soon as the wedding is over?
결혼식 끝나자마자?
The news has ended.
뉴스가 종료되었습니다.
Only the Zhong family knows each other.
Zhong 가족만이 서로를 알고 있습니다.
over the past few days
지난 며칠간
I haven't heard any news.
나는 어떤 소식도 듣지 못했습니다.
Actually it's not a big problem.
실제로 그것은 큰 문제가 아닙니다.
Hua Sen lost consciousness.
화센은 의식을 잃었다.
It came from my senior in his wife's room .
첩의 방에서 제 선배에게서 온 거예요.
No one knows exactly what happened.
정확히 무슨 일이 일어났는지는 아무도 모릅니다.
So he was detained.
그래서 그는 구금되었습니다.
waiting for investigation
조사를 기다리고 있다
But now it's been more than 15 days.
하지만 이제 보름이 넘었습니다.
Why are you afraid of hope? I haven't done anything else yet.
왜 희망을 두려워합니까? 아직 다른 일은 하지 않았습니다.
This is a matter of life and death.
이것은 삶과 죽음의 문제입니다.
After all, he was Butler Hua's only son.
결국 그는 Butler Hua의 외아들이었습니다.
And a senior disciple is watching. How will the case be resolved?
그리고 선배 제자가 지켜보고 있습니다. 사건은 어떻게 해결될까요?
I didn't dare because I was afraid of hoping.
나는 희망하는 것이 두려워서 감히 감히 하지 못했습니다.
Please make a quick decision.
빠른 결정을 내리시기 바랍니다.
Yeran is a person who can distinguish.
예란은 구별할 수 있는 사람이다.
What is right and what is wrong?
무엇이 옳고 무엇이 그른가?
So he won't make a mistake. to the innocent
그래서 그는 실수하지 않을 것입니다. 무죄한 자에게
Achen must have been in a bad mood.
아첸은 기분이 좋지 않았나 보다.
Achen is a smart and kind-hearted kid.
아첸은 똑똑하고 마음이 착한 아이입니다.
Unfortunately, she had an older brother. who behaves very badly
불행하게도 그녀에게는 형이 있었습니다. 누가 아주 나쁘게 행동하는지
She was in a dilemma.
그녀는 딜레마에 빠졌습니다.
Not sure if that will help him or not.
그것이 그에게 도움이 될지 아닐지는 확실하지 않습니다.
I want to ask her...
나는 그녀에게 묻고 싶다...
Please stop by and see her and comfort her.
잠시 들러 그녀를 만나 위로를 해주세요.
But she doesn't seem to want to.
하지만 그녀는 원하지 않는 것 같습니다.
Get out of her house.
그녀의 집에서 나가세요.
government
정부
Madam, the weather is nice today.
부인, 오늘 날씨가 좋아요.
Do you want to go out for a walk?
산책하러 나가고 싶나요?
Chienji Brothers
치엔지 형제
What exactly happened to the mistress?
여주인에게 정확히 무슨 일이 일어난 걸까요?
Why was she quiet?
그녀는 왜 조용히 있었나요?
I lay like this all day
하루종일 이렇게 누워있어
Young Master Hua is still in prison.
Hua Young Master는 아직 감옥에 있습니다.
Why didn't the hostess do anything?
여주인은 왜 아무것도 하지 않았나요?
The hostess must have been very distraught.
여주인은 매우 정신이 나갔을 것입니다.
But the owner did not let this happen.
그러나 주인은 이 일을 놔두지 않았습니다.
What can a mistress do?
여주인은 무엇을 할 수 있습니까?
So what should we do?
그럼 우리는 어떻게 해야 할까요?
I can't leave you depressed like this.
여주인님을 이대로 우울하게 놔둘 수는 없습니다.
We said and did everything we could.
우리는 할 수 있는 모든 것을 말하고 행했습니다.
The owner still refused to continue.
주인은 여전히 ​​​​계속하기를 거부했습니다.
The hostess chose to remain quiet.
여주인은 조용히 있기를 선택했습니다.
There is nothing we can do about this situation .
이 상황에 대해 우리가 할 수 있는 일은 아무것도 없습니다.
Grandfather's Wife You really paint a beautiful picture.
할아버지의 아내 정말 아름다운 그림을 그리시네요.
no.
아니요.
She refused to leave the house.
그녀는 집 밖으로 나가기를 거부했습니다.
It's already been 15 days.
벌써 보름이 지났습니다.
And not much was done.
그리고 별로 한 것도 없습니다.
If she just stands still and does nothing.
만약 그녀가 가만히 서서 아무것도 하지 않는다면.
Not afraid of being called cold-blooded
냉혈한 사람이라고 불리는 것을 두려워하지 않습니다
I'll give her some praise.
나는 그녀에게 약간의 칭찬을 해줄 것이다.
But if she dared to help Hua Sen
하지만 만약 그녀가 감히 Hua Sen을 도왔다면
I didn't hesitate. to use this
나는 주저하지 않았다. 이것을 이용하기 위해
And dragged her through the mud too
그리고 그녀도 진흙 속으로 끌고 갔어
But I'm afraid to hope.
하지만 희망하기가 두렵습니다.
Just put Hua Sen in jail.
그냥 Hua Sen을 감옥에 가두세요.
I didn't do anything more.
나는 그 이상 아무것도 하지 않았다.
I am in no hurry.
나는 서두르지 않습니다.
What's wrong with your hands?
손에 무슨 문제가 있는 걸까요?
are you okay.
괜찮아요.
Is my head heavy?
내 머리가 무거운가?
No, it's okay.
아니요 괜찮아요.
Where are they all?
그들은 모두 어디에 있습니까?
There are no maids to be seen around here.
이 주변에는 하녀가 보이지 않습니다.
I myself don't know.
나 자신도 모른다.
Come and talk to me for a moment.
잠시 와서 나랑 얘기 좀 하자.
Now I have opened my eyes.
이제 나는 눈을 떴습니다.
I haven't asked you about this yet since you came .
네가 온 이후로 아직 이것에 대해서는 물어보지 않았습니다.
Is your family in Hwangcheong?
가족이 황청에 있나요?
No, it's okay.
아니요 괜찮아요.
They were in a remote village.
그들은 외딴 마을에 있었습니다.
My parents don't have money to support me.
우리 부모님은 나를 부양할 돈이 없습니다.
Because of the famine situation
기근상황 때문에
So he sold me into slavery. Gift it to a wealthy family
그래서 그는 나를 노예로 팔았습니다. 부유한 가족에게 선물하세요
You have entered the Zhong Clan Palace.
당신은 종씨궁에 입장했습니다.
Wasn't it last year when we conscripted the Guard ?
우리가 경비병을 징집했을 때 작년이 아니었나요?
I was sold to another family.
나는 다른 가족에게 팔렸습니다.
And get out of there
그리고 거기서 탈출해
Then you...
그럼 당신은 ...
I think it will be difficult.
어려울 것 같아요.
Don't do it again.
다시는 하지 마세요.
not anymore
더 이상은 아니야
You still hate that rich family.
당신은 아직도 그 부유한 가족을 싫어합니다.
Is this bad for you?
당신에게 좋지 않은 일인가요?
No, it's okay.
아니요 괜찮아요.
why?
왜?
Because I got it...
내가 받았으니까...
Why did you call me here?
왜 나를 여기로 부르셨나요?
You're still doing well...
아직도 잘하시네요...
As always, win people's hearts.
언제나처럼 사람들의 마음을 얻으세요.
You have refined yourself. What a faithful servant.
당신은 자신을 세련시켰습니다. 정말 충실한 종입니다.
Sir, is there a problem with me?
선생님, 저한테 문제가 있으신가요?
Wasn't it you who wanted to meet me?
나랑 만나고 싶었던 사람은 너 아니었어?
I want to go...
나는 가고 싶다...
The maid has her own.
하녀는 자신의 것을 가지고 있습니다.
I have nothing to talk to you about.
나는 당신과 이야기 할 것이 없습니다.
Teacher, please go back.
선생님, 돌아가세요.
You haven't gone anywhere. It's already been 15 days.
당신은 아무데도 가지 않았습니다. 벌써 보름이 지났습니다.
What exactly do you plan on doing?
정확히 무엇을 할 생각인가요?
What did I do wrong?
내가 뭘 잘못했나요?
Or your prejudices make you think
아니면 당신의 편견이 당신을 생각하게 만듭니다
I definitely did something wrong.
나는 확실히 뭔가 잘못했습니다.
Are you blaming me?
나를 비난하고 있습니까?
What good is it to criticize you?
당신을 비난해봤자 무슨 소용이 있나요?
It just annoys me.
그것은 나를 짜증나게 할 뿐입니다.
You seem to like talking back and forth.
당신은 앞뒤로 이야기하는 것을 좋아하는 것 같습니다 .
Before, you didn't want to listen to me.
전에는 당신이 내 말을 듣고 싶어하지 않았습니다.
I don't want to talk to you right now either.
나도 지금 당장은 너랑 얘기하고 싶지 않아.
My heart aches.
내 마음이 괴로워요.
I'm not in the mood to argue with you.
나는 당신과 논쟁할 기분이 아닙니다.
Don't mess with me.
나한테 장난치지 마.
Huaqian
화첸
You can take my brother's life.
당신은 내 동생의 생명을 빼앗을 수 있습니다.
If you want
네가 원한다면
Take what you are comfortable with.
당신이 편한 것을 가져 가라.
government
정부
I asked the owner to come see me. without your permission
나는 주인에게 나를 보러 오라고 요청했습니다. 당신의 허락 없이
Because I am very worried.
왜냐면 나는 매우 걱정이 되기 때문이다.
It's sad to see this.
이렇게 보니 슬프네요.
are you okay
괜찮아요
I don't blame you.
나는 당신을 비난하지 않습니다.
Ahian
아히안
Ah, Qian, I guess you didn’t buy it.
아 치안, 안 사셨나 보네요.
Good jewelry from when you get married.
결혼할 때부터 좋은 주얼리 .
So I went out and bought some nice jewelry for you.
그래서 나가서 당신을 위해 멋진 보석을 샀어요.
This is it.
이거 야.
Madam, it's time to go to bed.
부인, 이제 잠자리에 드실 시간이에요.
“I finally get it.”
"드디어 알겠습니다."
“Why was I born again? On my wedding night”
"나는 왜 다시 태어났는가? 결혼식날 밤에"
“I wish it had been sooner.”
"더 빨랐더라면 좋았을 텐데."
“I think it has to be that way.”
"그럴 수밖에 없을 것 같아."
“Close your eyes and close your eyes to protect the Fahrenheit family.”
"화씨 가족을 보호하기 위해 눈을 감고 눈을 감으십시오."
“I don’t even know what I did, it’s so...”
"내가 무슨 짓을 했는지도 모르고, 너무..."
Get ready tomorrow morning.
내일 아침 준비하세요.
I will go out.
나는 밖으로 나갈 것이다.
Madam, where are you going?
부인, 어디 가시나요?
Let me check out my store.
내 가게를 확인해 보겠습니다.
Sir, I will prepare everything tomorrow morning .
선생님, 내일 아침에 제가 모든 것을 준비하겠습니다.
are you okay.
괜찮아요.
Go to the store in the morning and tell them.
아침에 가게에 가서 말하세요.
Please prepare a ledger.
장부를 준비해주세요.
I'll go in in the afternoon.
오후에 들어갈게요.
To check your profit or loss
손익을 확인하려면
And see how much money you can withdraw.
그리고 얼마나 많은 돈을 인출할 수 있는지 확인해 보세요.
Madam , do you need money?
부인 , 돈 필요해요?
yes
예
Money is power
돈은 힘이다
no matter where you are
당신이 어디에 있든 상관없이
This is last month's ledger.
이것은 지난 달의 장부입니다.
underfoot
발 밑에
The wife left home.
부인이 집을 나갔습니다.
Please help me sort this out quickly.
빨리 이 일을 정리할 수 있게 도와주세요.
Accept it.
그것을 받아들이십시오.
Be sure to come and get it.
꼭 오셔서 받아보세요.
Prepare bills according to the amount.
금액에 맞게 지폐를 준비하세요..
Ready to withdraw
인출할 수 있는 준비가 되어 있는 것
I will send someone to pick you up.
당신을 데리러 갈 사람을 보내겠습니다.
within a few days
며칠 안에
Please, mistress.
부탁해요, 여주인님.
Please take care of yourself.
자신을 돌봐주세요.
Come on, you've been out of the house with me all day.
가자, 당신은 하루 종일 나와 함께 집 밖에 있었어요.
I'll treat you all to dinner.
내가 너희 모두에게 저녁을 대접할게.
The food is ready. bon appetite.
음식이 준비되었습니다. 맛있게 드세요.
What are you doing standing there?
거기 서서 뭐해요?
Come sit down and eat.
와서 앉아서 먹어요.
Hurry up!
서둘러요!
The food at this restaurant is delicious.
이 식당의 음식은 맛있어요.
Eat again, you too, eat now
또 먹어라 너도 지금 먹어라
Aren't you Rong Zhou?
당신은 Rong Zhou가 아닌가요?
We haven't seen each other for half a year.
우리는 반년 동안 서로를 보지 못했습니다.
are you okay.
너는 괜찮아.
sorry.
죄송합니다.
I can interrupt you. bon appetite.
나는 당신을 방해할 수 있습니다. 맛있게 드세요.
If you need anything, please call me anytime.
필요한 것이 있으면 언제든지 저에게 전화하세요.
Do you know him?
그를 아니?
Before I applied to the military guard
제가 군경비대에 지원하기 전에는
I was here for a few months when I was working as a regular employee .
일반 직원으로 일하던 시절 나는 여기에 몇 달 동안 있었습니다.
You are really experienced.
정말 경험이 많으시군요.
really at this age
정말 이 나이에
Now, eat again.
자, 또 먹어라.
excellent.
훌륭한.
wow!
우와!
park the carriage
마차를 주차하세요
Let's take a walk before going home.
집에 가기 전에 산책하자.
Please, mistress.
부탁해요, 여주인님.
- Take it back - Take it back.
- 다시 가져가세요
Hey, this also adds a lot of scent.
이봐, 이것도 만 리 향기를 더한다.
Accept it.
그것을 받아들이십시오.
Since I was born again six months ago
육 개월 전에 내가 다시 태어난 이후로
Didn't go out. Take a walk at night.
나가지 않았습니다. 밤에 산책을 해보세요.
In the wasteland after seeing the drought
가뭄을 본 후 황무지에서
The market is crowded with people right now...
지금 사람들로 붐비는 시장은...
quite beautiful
꽤 아름답다
Please give me directions.
나에게 방향을 알려주십시오.
Do it again.
다시 할.
Why do you think you've grown taller again?
왜 또 키가 커진 것 같지?
Teacher, why did you come out alone ?
선생님, 왜 혼자 나오 셨나요 ?
You haven't gone anywhere. A month has already passed.
당신은 아무데도 가지 않았습니다. 벌써 한 달이 지났습니다.
Why did you suddenly leave home today?
오늘 왜 갑자기 집을 나갔나요?
Does your lineage belong to the Zhong family?
귀하의 계통은 Zhong 가문에 속합니까 ?
Otherwise how would I know what I did ?
그렇지 않으면 내가 무슨 짓을 했는지 어떻게 알겠어요 ?
what do you think?
어떻게 생각하나요?
Since we met, let's go.
만났으니 가자.
Why are you looking for me?
왜 나를 찾고 있나요?
I want to take you somewhere.
나는 당신을 어떤 곳으로 데려가고 싶습니다.
let's go.
갑시다.
Pay tribute to Mother Meng
멩 어머니에게 경의를 표하십시오
- Are your feet inside or not? - Yes, teacher.
- 발이 안쪽에 있나요, 없나요? - 네, 선생님.
If so, can you tell my master ?
그렇다면 내 주인님께 알려 주실 수 있나요 ?
My lady made curry soup for me.
내 아가씨가 나를 위해 카레 수프를 만들어줬다고.
Because the weather is cold today.
오늘은 날씨가 추우니까.
Your Majesty has an order.
전하께 명령이 있습니다.
you are busy
당신이 바쁘다고
Therefore, entry by outsiders is prohibited.
따라서 외부인의 출입은 금지되어 있습니다.
My lady, how can I be an outsider?
나의 아가씨여, 내가 어떻게 아웃사이더가 될 수 있습니까?
Please forgive me, Teacher Meng.
용서해주세요, 멩 선생님.
I cannot disobey your master's orders.
나는 당신 주인의 명령을 거역할 수 없습니다.
Then you go and inform your master.
그러면 너는 가서 주인에게 알린다.
I'll quickly pass on the curry and leave.
카레는 빨리 넘기고 떠날게요.
Mrs. Meng, please pass me the curry soup.
멍씨 부인, 카레 수프를 건네주세요.
I will send it to you directly.
제가 직접 보내드리겠습니다.
Why is there no butler Gao?
집사 가오는 왜 없나요?
He is there to serve you from within.
그는 내부에서 당신을 섬기기 위해 거기에 있습니다.
Anyway, thank you.
아무튼 감사 해요.
No problem, Madam Meng.
문제 없습니다, 멩 부인.
I just received the news.
방금 소식을 받았어요.
The matter between Hua Qian and the Master did not coincide.
Hua Qian과 스승의 문제는 일치하지 않았습니다.
Day before yesterday
그저께
I was really surprised today...
오늘 진짜 놀랐다...
I have a chance to meet people. Tears wiped at other people's knees.
사람들을 만날 기회가 있다 눈물이 다른 사람의 무릎을 닦았습니다.
really good
정말 좋다
- I really like it - Miss...
- 정말 좋아요 - 아가씨...
If only I saw two or three more people
두세명만 더 봤다면
In this world it would be good to suffer.
이 세상에서는 고통받는 것이 좋을 것입니다.
"Tower that Reaches the Stars"
"별에 닿는 탑"
Where are we?
여긴 어디야?
Uam Dara Tower
우암다라타워
The first floor was where the Jong family lived.
1층은 종 가족이 살았던 곳이었습니다.
Releases scent during the day
낮에는 향기를 발산
upstairs
위층
This is where medicinal herbs are stored.
약초를 보관하는 곳입니다.
No one went up at night.
밤에는 아무도 올라가지 않았습니다.
Why did you bring me here?
왜 나를 여기로 데려왔나요?
Let's go upstairs.
위층으로 가자.
Walk?
걸어가?
How will you get there if you don't walk?
걷지 않는다면 어떻게 갈 것인가?
Teacher, please go up.
선생님, 꼭 올라가 보세요.
Please excuse me first.
먼저 실례하겠습니다.
How many floors are there in total?
총 몇 층인가요?
eleven
열하나
Which floor should I go to?
어느 층으로 갈까요?
11th floor
11층
Sir, do you think so?
선생님, 그렇게 생각하시나요?
Will I have the intelligence to reach the 11th level?
나는 11번째 수준에 도달할 수 있는 지능을 갖게 될까요?
If you get tired in the middle, you can take a break.
중간에 피곤하면 쉬어도 돼요.
That is... I suddenly felt pain in my chest.
즉... 갑자기 가슴에 통증이 느껴졌습니다.
It's probably a side effect.
아마도 부작용인 것 같습니다.
From arrow wounds
화살로 인한 상처에서
I am weak and sick.
나는 약하고 아프다.
I can't climb a lot of stairs.
계단을 많이 오를 수 없습니다.
I'd rather go home and get some rest.
차라리 집에 가서 좀 쉬는 게 낫겠어요.
Dr. Wu said.
우 박사가 말했다.
Climbing stairs
계단 오르기
This is a way to make your body stronger.
몸을 튼튼하게 만드는 방법입니다.
So you are okay.
그러니 당신은 괜찮습니다.
But it really breaks my heart.
그런데 정말 가슴이 아프네요.
Dr. Wu may be wrong.
우 박사님이 틀렸을 수도 있어요.
Suddenly the pain subsided.
갑자기 통증이 가라앉았습니다.
let's go.
갑시다.
Arrived
도착했다
Come this way.
이리 오세요.
I'm so tired I can't move.
너무 피곤해서 움직일 수 없어요.
I'll show you something good.
좋은 걸 보여드릴게요.
It's so dark.
이렇게 어두워요.
Is there anything to see?
볼 게 있나요?
Now you don't seem to be afraid of me.
이제 당신은 나를 두려워하지 않는 것 같습니다.
Shall I drag you away?
내가 당신을 끌고 갈까요?
Sir, is there nothing better to do?
선생님, 더 좋은 일은 없나요?
It wasn't easy to find time.
시간을 내기가 쉽지 않더군요.
If you look down from here
여기서 아래를 내려다 보면
Do you feel it?
당신은 그것을 느끼나요?
Everything is under your feet.
모든 것이 당신의 발 아래 있습니다.
Suddenly all my problems disappeared.
갑자기 모든 문제가 사라졌습니다.
The problem won't go away.
문제는 사라지지 않을 것입니다.
Just by standing high up
높은 곳에 서 있다는 것만으로도
When we're high up
우리가 높은 곳에 있을 때
We will see less.
우리는 더 적게 볼 것입니다.
You don't know what you're talking about.
당신은 당신이 무슨 말을하는지 모르겠어요.
Words I've never heard before
한 번도 들어본 적 없는 말
“Stand tall and look far” or
"우뚝 서서 멀리 보세요" 또는
This may not always be the case.
항상 그런 것은 아닐 수도 있습니다.
If we take a closer look, what do we get?
더 자세히 살펴보면 무엇을 얻을 수 있나요?
To see the full photo
전체 사진을 보시려면
We may be biased.
우리는 편견에 사로잡혀 있을 수 있습니다.
And we can't see what's in front of us
그리고 우리 앞에 있는 것을 볼 수 없습니다
You have to see it with your own eyes.
직접 눈으로 확인해야 합니다.
understand
이해하다
If you don't try today
오늘 시도하지 않으면
go up the stairs
계단을 올라가다
You can only imagine the scenery.
풍경 만 상상할 수 있습니다.
what everyone is talking about
모두가 얘기하는 것
If you're afraid of that, you overlooked something.
그게 두렵다면 뭔가를 간과했다
Pay more attention to things around you.
주변의 것들에 더 많은 관심을 기울이십시오.
Instead of ignoring it
그것을 외면하는 대신
Your Majesty, you brought me here.
폐하, 저를 여기로 데려오셨습니다.
Is it just to enjoy the scenery?
단지 경치를 감상하기 위해서인가요?
Look at the way you said no.
당신이 거절한 방식을 보세요.
mother's invitation
어머니의 초대장
So I generously shared my views.
그래서 나는 내 견해를 아낌없이 나누었습니다.
This wide and beautiful place with you
너와 함께하는 이 넓고 아름다운 곳
The general public has no opportunity to see
일반 대중이 볼 기회가 없는
Why are you so kind to me?
왜 나한테 이렇게 친절해?
Become an Ally Shouldn't we help each other?
동맹이 되세요 우리는 서로 도와야 하지 않나요?
“Do we help each other?”
"서로 도와주나요?"
“Is it possible? He had the same intention.”
"가능한가요? 그 사람도 같은 의도였다고"
“With Wusuomu”
"우쑤오무와 함께"
“He wanted me to be conscious.”
"그는 내가 의식하기를 원했어요."
“Then pull Zong Yeran back.”
“그럼 종예란을 뒤로 끌어내세요.”
“ A woman he likes so he can marry her .”
"그가 결혼할 수 있도록 그 사람이 좋아하는 여자야."
- What are you planning to do? - I'm just...
- 뭘 할 계획이에요? - 난 그냥...
I didn't bring you here. to make him commit suicide
나는 당신을 여기로 데려온 것이 아닙니다. 자살하게 하려고
Sir , don't you think this is inappropriate?
선생님 , 이건 부적절하다고 생각하지 않나요?
Don't be afraid.
두려워하지 마십시오.
To this star that reaches the tower at night
밤이면 탑에 닿는 이 별에
I only have my people.
내 사람들만 있어요.
No one can see us.
아무도 우리를 볼 수 없습니다.
Sir, you support me.
선생님, 저를 지지해 주시네요.
Are you cheating on your husband?
남편을 속이고 있나요?
Are you sure you're saying this again?
설마 또 이런 말을 해?
you like...
당신은 좋아합니까?
she is married
그녀는 결혼했다.
Do you still miss her?
아직도 그녀를 그리워하시나요?
yes
예
She is a really lucky woman.
그녀는 정말로 운이 좋은 여자다.
“Mu Yao has always been lucky.”
"Mu Yao는 항상 운이 좋았습니다."
“There are a lot of men.”
"남자가 많아요."
“I love you unconditionally.”
"나는 조건 없이 당신을 사랑합니다."
“It’s different from me.”
"나랑은 달라."
“It doesn’t matter how hard you try.”
"아무리 노력해도 상관없어"
“I can’t change.”
"나는 바꿀 수 없다."
“What prejudices they may have about me.”
"그들이 나에 대해 가질 수 있는 편견."
“One mistake leads to another mistake.”
"한 번의 실수로 인해 또 실수야."
Would you like some?
좀 드시겠어요?
What is that?
그것은 무엇입니까?
Wollu fermented liquor
월루 발효주
Drinking it is said to help relieve anxiety.
마시면 불안감 해소에 도움이 된다고 합니다.
You can only drink it. Dara Lim Towerman
에서만 마실 수 있습니다. 다라 림 타워만
Not for sale
비매품
Would you like to relieve your worries?
걱정을 해소하시겠습니까?
It's easier said than done.
말하기는 쉽습니다.
Why didn't you tell me?
왜 나에게 말하지 않았나요?
Have another bottle.
한 병 더 드세요.
Just take one small cup like this.
이렇게 작은 컵 하나만 가져가세요.
really stingy
정말 인색하다
Do you know what Yue Lu fermented liquor is?
월루(Yue Lu) 발효주가 무엇인지 아시나요?
You said it helps relieve anxiety, right ?
불안을 해소하는 데 도움이 된다고 하셨죠 ?
I think it helps ease some of the anxiety.
걱정을 덜어주는 데 도움이 된다고 생각합니다.
why?
왜?
It is a fragrant fermented liquor. That's powerful...
향기로운 발효주입니다. 그게 힘이 있구나...
the most powerful in the world
세계에서 가장 강력한
fragrant fermented liquor
향기로운 발효주
Strongest?
가장 강한가?
Sir, please have a drink. Please excuse me first.
선생님, 한잔 드세요. 먼저 실례하겠습니다.
Where are you going in such a hurry?
그렇게 서둘러 어디로 가시나요?
- I'll go with you. - It's okay, sir.
- 제가 같이 갈게요 - 괜찮습니다, 선생님
There is a maid, don't follow her.
하녀가 있어요 따라오지 마세요
It would be bad if someone saw us.
누군가 우리를 보면 나쁠 것입니다.
“Wolu Fermented Wine”
"월루 발효주"
government
정부
- Hostess - Let's go home.
- 여주인 - 집에 가자.
the opposite
그 반대
government
정부
- Hostess - I'm not good at drinking.
- 여주인 - 저는 술을 잘 못해요.
I'm afraid I'll embarrass myself
나 자신이 당황스러워질까 봐
Please help me take me downstairs. Hurry up!
저를 아래층으로 데려가는 것을 도와주세요. 서둘러요.
Madam, I know you are weak-willed.
부인, 당신은 의지가 약한 것을 알고 있습니다.
why...
왜...
Hurry up!
서둘러요!
- Bring me more alcohol - sir.
- 술 더 가져오세요 - 주인님.
Put me down, I want one more drink
날 내려놔, 한 잔 더 마시고 싶어
let me go
나를 놔줘
Drop me off
내려 줘
I want to drink again.
또 마시고 싶어요.
- Hostess - Please disappoint me.
- 여주인 - 실망시켜주세요.
- I want to drink more - Madam.
- 술을 더 마시고 싶어요 - 부인
Put me down, I want to drink more.
날 내려놔, 난 술 더 마시고 싶어.
No, mistress.
아니, 여주인.
- mistress
- 여주인
I want to drink again.
또 마시고 싶어요.
I'll go for a carriage ride.
마차를 타러 갈게요.
Take it, mistress.
받아요, 여주인.
I want to drink again.
또 마시고 싶어요.
Please let go. I want to drink it.
놔주세요. 마시고 싶어요.
- I want a drink - Madam.
- 술을 마시고 싶어요 - 부인.
Then I'll go for a carriage ride instead.
그럼 대신 마차를 타러 갈게요.
- Uam Dara Tower... - Take care of her.
- 우암다라타워... - 그녀를 보살펴 줘.
- The liquor of Uamdara Pagoda - Remember
- 우암다라탑의 술 - 기억하라
Do not allow anyone to see your mistress in this state.
이 상태에서는 누구도 당신의 여주인을 보지 못하게 하십시오.
- I understand - I want to drink more.
- 이해해요 - 술 더 마시고 싶어요
Where are you going in such a hurry?
그렇게 서둘러 어디로 가시나요?
- Hostess - I'd like to have another drink.
- 여주인 - 한 잔 더 마시고 싶어요.
government
정부
Please stand up.
일어나주세요.
- It's too bright. - Madam, please don't stab me in the eye.
- 너무 밝네요 - 부인, 제 눈을 찌르지 마세요.
It's really shiny.
정말 반짝반짝해요.
So beautiful
너무 아름다워
Please stand up.
일어나주세요.
It smells so good.
냄새가 너무 좋아요.
Your hair will be very soft.
당신의 머리카락은 매우 부드럽습니다.
What oils do you use to nourish your hair?
머리카락에 영양을 공급하기 위해 어떤 오일을 사용하시나요?
Why is your hair so soft?
머리카락이 왜 이렇게 부드러워요?
It smells so good.
냄새가 너무 좋아요.
do not do that...
하지 마라...
so soft
너무 부드러워
cotton candy
솜사탕
It's so soft.
너무 부드럽습니다.
Why isn't it sweet?
왜 달콤하지 않습니까?
Doesn't she seem like she's running fast?
그녀는 빨리 달리는 것 같지 않나요?
I will send someone tomorrow to pick it up.
내일 사람을 보내서 가져가도록 하겠습니다.
I will prepare for you.
내가 당신을 위해 준비하겠습니다.
We have a problem for you, Guard Hua.
당신에게 문제가 생겼습니다, 경비병 Hua.
I didn't mean to do that.
그럴 생각은 없었어요.
Why is the heroine crying?
여주인공은 왜 울어요?
Let's take a horse-drawn carriage ride.
말이 끄는 마차를 타보자.
"Extra Scenes"
"추가 장면"
I didn't mean to do that.
그럴 생각은 없었어요.
Madam, please.
부인, 부탁드립니다.
I don’t know if she is Linglong.
그녀가 Linglong인지는 모르겠습니다.
after i was born again
내가 다시 태어난 후
I have never seen Linglong. At the Hua Family Mansion
나는 링롱을 본 적이 없습니다. 후아 패밀리 맨션에서
I don’t know if she is Linglong.
그녀가 Linglong인지는 모르겠습니다.
sorry.
죄송합니다.
No one believes me.
아무도 나를 믿지 않습니다.
And no one wants to help me.
그리고 아무도 나를 돕고 싶어하지 않습니다.
Everyone blames me for everything that happened.
모두가 나에게 일어난 모든 일을 비난합니다 .
oh my god?
어떡해?
I am not an all-knowing god.
나는 모든 것을 아는 신이 아닙니다.
How do I find out what happened?
무슨 일이 일어났는지 어떻게 알 수 있나요?
behind my back
내 등 뒤에
Now I'm back to living my life again.
이제 나는 다시 내 삶을 살기 위해 돌아왔습니다.
Why is everyone still like this? With you
왜 아직도 다들 이러는 걸까요? 너와 함께
I am not a loner at all.
나는 조금도 외톨이가 아닙니다.
Even though I knew the fat man had done something wrong.
그 뚱뚱한 남자가 뭔가 잘못했다는 걸 알면서도.
oh my god?
어떡해?
I don't want to die.
나는 죽고 싶지 않아요.
i want to live
나는 살고 싶다
I just want to live.
나는 단지 살고 싶다.
I never want to see my family die again .
다시 는 가족이 죽는 걸 보고 싶지 않아요 .
I'm sorry, Linglong.
미안해요, 링롱.
sorry.
죄송합니다.